Guide to the John McDonald Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1890-1998; Series II; 26; (26 boxes)
  - Books
    - The Complete Fly Fisherman (1970 and 1989 editions)
      - Correspondence
        - Lyons, Nick, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 483)
        - Theodore Gordon Flyfishers, 1967-1990 (Box 15, Folder 484)
        - Miscellaneous, 1968-1989 (Box 15, Folder 485)
      - Research notes, 1988-1989, undated (Box 15, Folder 486-489)
      - "Corrections to Gordon book", 1949-1988 (Box 15, Folder 490)
      - Drafts, 1989 Mar (Box 15, Folder 491-492)
      - Drafts, 1989 Apr (Box 15, Folder 493-497)
      - Drafts, undated (Box 15, Folder 498-499)
      - Galleys, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 500)
      - List of signed books and inscriptions, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 501)
      - Fan mail, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 502)
      - Reviews, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 503)
    - Fisherman's Bounty (1970): essay on Berners and Gordon (Box 15, Folder 504)
    - The Game of Business (1975)
      - Correspondence
        - Dodd, Mead & Company, 1967-1974, undated (Box 16, Folder 505)
        - Doubleday & Company, 1967-1986 (Box 16, Folder 506-508)
        - Harold Matson & Company, 1967-1986 (Box 16, Folder 509)
        - Land Foundation, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 510)
        - National Science Foundation, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 511-512)
        - Rand Corporation, 1967-1969 (Box 16, Folder 513)
        - Relm Foundation, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 514)
        - Rockefeller Foundation, 1968-1971 (Box 16, Folder 515)
      - Contracts and estimates, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 516)
      - Outlines, 1967-1974, undated (Box 16, Folder 517-519)
      - Research material
        Arranged in alphabetical order by correspondent, and thereunder, if warranted, by correspondence, notes, and writings
        - Banks, Louis, 1968-1970, undated (Box 16, Folder 520)
        - Bartels, Richard, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 521)
        - Bickner, Robert E.
          See: Alexander Mood
        - Brams, Steven J.
          - Correspondence, 1977-1996 (Box 16, Folder 522-523)
          - Notes, 1977-1995, undated (Box 16, Folder 524)
          - Writings, 1975-1990, undated (Box 16, Folder 525-529)
        - Buchler, Ira R.
          - Correspondence and notes, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 530)
          - Writings, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 531)
        - Cornwall, Richard R., 1969 (Box 16, Folder 532)
        - Harsanyi, John C.
          - Correspondence, 1968-1975 (Box 16, Folder 533)
          - Notes, 1969, undated (Box 16, Folder 534-535)
          - Writings, 1966-1968 (Box 16, Folder 536)
        - Littlechild, Stephen C., 1975-1979 (Box 16, Folder 537)
        - Lucas, William F.
          - Correspondence, 1970-1980 (Box 17, Folder 538)
          - Notes, 1970-1974, undated (Box 17, Folder 539-545)
          - Writings, 1969-1994, undated (Box 17, Folder 546-547)
        - Luykx, Nicolaas G. M., 1957 (Box 17, Folder 548)
        - Mood, Alexander McFarlane, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 549)
        - Morgenstern, Oskar
          - Notes, 1969-1977, undated (Box 17, Folder 550)
          - Writings, 1951-1975, undated (Box 17, Folder 551)
        - Novick, David, 1969-1971 (Box 17, Folder 552)
        - Parker, Sanford, undated (Box 17, Folder 553)
        - Paxson, Edwin W.
          - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 554)
          - Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 555-556)
        - Rand Corporation, notes, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 557-558)
        - Shapley, Lloyd S.
          - Correspondence, 1968-1970, undated (Box 17, Folder 559)
          - Notes, 1968-1971 (Box 17, Folder 560-569)
          - Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 570-571)
          - Writings, 1961-1972, undated (Box 18, Folder 572-575)
        - Shubik, Martin
          - Correspondence, 1955-1975 (Box 18, Folder 576)
          - Notes, 1968-1970, undated (Box 18, Folder 577-582)
        - Tukey, John W., 1953, undated (Box 18, Folder 583)
        - Walt Disney Productions, 1966-1974 (Box 18, Folder 584-585)
      - Business decisions survey
        - Questionnaire, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 586)
        - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 587)
        - Interviewee key sheet, 1968 Aug 20 (Box 18, Folder 588)
        - Notes, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 589-590)
        - Responses A, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 591-594)
        - Responses B 1-20, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 595-604)
        - Responses B 21-24, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 605-608)
        - Responses C - D, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 609-613)
        - Responses E - J, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 614-624)
      - Notes, miscellaneous, 1968-1980, undated (Box 19, Folder 625-642)
      - Writings of others, miscellaneous, 1946-1976, undated (Box 20, Folder 643-647)
      - Publishing notes, 1975-1991 (Box 20, Folder 648)
      - Biographical statements, circa 1975 (Box 20, Folder 649)
      - Jacket copy notes, undated (Box 20, Folder 650)
      - Promotional materials, 1975, undated (Box 20, Folder 651)
      - Press notices and reviews, 1975-1977 (Box 20, Folder 652-659)
      - Fan mail, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 660-661)
      - German edition, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 662)
      - Japanese edition, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 663)
      - Russian edition, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 664-666)
      - Abridged version, in Book Digest Magazine, 1975 August (Box 20, Folder 667)
      - The Game of Business volume, labeled "Work copy #2" and annotated by McDonald, 1975-1977, undated (Box 20, Folder 668)
    - A Ghost's Memoir (2002)
      - Correspondence
        - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1960-1990 (Box 21, Folder 669)
        - Cox, Hugh, 1961-1964 (Box 21, Folder 670)
        - Donovan, Hedley, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 671)
        - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1956-1991 (Box 21, Folder 672-673)
        - Harold Matson Company, Inc., 1993-1996 (Box 21, Folder 674)
        - Lyons, Nick, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 675)
        - Seligman, Daniel, 1991-1997 (Box 21, Folder 676)
        - Sloan, Alfred P. (Alfred Pritchard), 1951-1965 (Box 21, Folder 677-679)
        - Stevens, Catharine, 1951-1991 (Box 21, Folder 680-681)
          See also: Stevens, Catharine
        - Miscellaneous, 1951-1995 (Box 21, Folder 682)
      - Research files
        Includes many primary documents pertaining to the 1964 publication, My Years with General Motors.
        - Biographical information, 1993-1996 (Box 21, Folder 683)
        - Chronologies and outlines, 1959-1998 (Box 21, Folder 684)
        - Newspaper clippings, 1973-1992
        - Notes, 1952-1998 (Box 21, Folder 685-715)
        - Notes, 1962-1998 (Box 22, Folder 716-763)
        - Notes, 1962-1998 (Box 23, Folder 764-772)
        - Notes, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 773-774)
        - Notes, 1990-1998 (Box 23, Folder 775-789)
        - Notes, undated (Box 23, Folder 790-793)
      - Manuscript drafts
        - "First draft", undated (Box 23, Folder 794)
        - Preface and outline, undated (Box 23, Folder 795)
        - Miscellaneous pages and inserts, 1992-1995 (Box 23, Folder 796)
        - Draft, 1992 Oct 28 (Box 23, Folder 797)
        - Draft, with pages cut, 1993 Oct 29 (Box 23, Folder 798-799)
        - Draft, 1994 May 30 (Box 24, Folder 800-801)
        - Draft, 1994 Sep 13 (Box 24, Folder 802-803)
        - Draft, 1995 Mar 25 (Box 24, Folder 804-807)
        - Chapter outline, 1995 Apr 12 (Box 24, Folder 808)
        - Draft, 1995 May 7 (Box 24, Folder 809-810)
        - Chapter outline, 1995 May 8 (Box 24, Folder 811)
        - Draft, copy one, 1995 Sep (Box 24, Folder 812-813)
        - Draft, copy two, 1995 Sep (Box 24, Folder 814-815)
        - Draft, edited copy, 1998 Jul (Box 24, Folder 816-817)
        - Draft, revised copy, 1998 Jul (Box 24, Folder 818-819)
    - My Years with General Motors, by Alfred P. Sloan Jr. (1964)
      See also the Research files for A Ghost's Memoir above, which include many primary documents for My Years with General Motors.
      - Big business project
        - Correspondence with Alfred P. Sloan Jr., 1949-1953 (Box 25, Folder 820-821)
        - "Business Bigness and Business Efficiency," by Alfred P. Sloan, typescript, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 822)
        - McDonald comments on Sloan essay, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 823)
        - GM documents, 1944-1949 (Box 25, Folder 824)
        - GM policies, 1920-1925 (Box 25, Folder 825)
        - Research notes and material, 1949-1953, undated (Box 25, Folder 826-829)
      - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1954-1959 (Box 25, Folder 830)
      - Photographs, 1958-1964 (Box 25, Folder 831)
        Includes Sloan, contract signing, project staff
      - Project memos, internal, 1955-1958 (Box 25, Folder 832)
      - Publishing contract memos, 1956-1963 (Box 25, Folder 833)
      - Research files
        - Newspaper clippings, 1952-1964 (Box 25, Folder 834)
        - Distribution, miscellaneous, undated (Box 25, Folder 835)
        - General Motors records
          - Annual reports (1922-1937, 1958), 1958, undated (Box 25, Folder 836)
          - Annual reports, notes on, undated (Box 25, Folder 837)
          - "Basic documents", undated (Box 25, Folder 838-844)
            Internal documents and reports copied from GM office files
          - Executive committee minutes (1918-1925), notes on, undated (Box 25, Folder 845)
          - Finance committee minutes (1920-1924), notes on, undated (Box 25, Folder 846)
          - Financial Policy committee reports, 1951 (Box 25, Folder 847)
          - General sales committee minutes (1925), notes on, undated (Box 25, Folder 848)
          - Promotional brochures and corporate organization charts, 1958-1959 (Box 25, Folder 849)
        - Interviews with GM executives, 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 850-852)
        - Laird & Company, undated (Box 25, Folder 853)
        - Market, 1956-1959 (Box 25, Folder 854)
        - Notes and notebooks, 1954-1962, undated (Box 26, Folder 855-863)
        - Organization: Chandler, Alfred D., Jr.
          - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 864)
          - Memos, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 865-866)
          - Chapter IV drafts, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 867)
          - Research reports, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 868-869)
        - Organization: Distribution, undated (Box 26, Folder 870)
        - Organization: Mooney [James F.] notes, undated (Box 26, Folder 871)
        - Organization: Operating policy, undated (Box 26, Folder 872)
        - Photography for book (notes), 1959 (Box 26, Folder 873)
        - Production control, undated (Box 26, Folder 874-875)
        - Proving grounds, 1958, undated (Box 26, Folder 876)
        - Steckler, Herman, graphs, 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 877)
        - Sloan, Alfred P. (Alfred Pritchard)
          - Letter #1 to GM executives, with responses, 1954-1955 (Box 26, Folder 878-879)
          - Comments and suggestions on first draft, 1956-1957 (Box 26, Folder 880)
          - Comments and suggestions (by GM executives), 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 881-882)
          - Comments and suggestions (by GM executives), McDonald's copies, 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 883-884)
          - Comments and suggestions (by Sloan), 1955-1959 (Box 26, Folder 885-886)
          - Corrections and additions (by Sloan), 1962 (Box 26, Folder 887)
          - Correspondence: Chayne, Charles, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 888)
          - Correspondence: GM executives, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 889)
          - Correspondence: GM executives, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 890)
          - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1955-1959 (Box 26, Folder 891)
          - Expressions used, 1956-1958 (Box 26, Folder 892)
          - Interview, regarding the Depression years, 1956 Apr 12 (Box 26, Folder 893)
          - Project memos (to Sloan from McDonald), 1954-1959 (Box 27, Folder 894-895)
          - Resignation, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 896)
      - Manuscript drafts
        - Book outlines and chapter distribution lists, 1955-1959 (Box 27, Folder 897)
        - Volume I, copy 1, 1954 Dec 30 (Box 27, Folder 898)
        - Volume I, copy 2, 1954 Dec 30 (Box 27, Folder 899-900)
        - Chapter 2, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 901-902)
        - "Rough draft" intro, chapters 1-3, 1955 Mar (Box 27, Folder 903)
        - "First draft" part I, 1956 Apr (Box 27, Folder 904-905)
        - "First draft" chapters 1-3, 1956 May 1 (Box 27, Folder 906-908)
        - "Rough draft" part I, 1956 Aug (Box 27, Folder 909-910)
        - "Rough draft" part II, 1956 Aug (Box 27, Folder 911)
        - "Rough draft" revisions, chapters 5-6, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 912-913)
        - Preface, 1956-1959 (Box 27, Folder 914)
        - "Bradley chapter", 1957 (Box 27, Folder 915)
        - Acknowledgments by section, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 916)
        - Acknowledgments, GM people, 1957-1959 (Box 27, Folder 917)
        - Acknowledgments, miscellaneous, 1957-1959 (Box 27, Folder 918)
        - "Questions, saves, etc.", undated (Box 27, Folder 919)
        - Part I, bound copy, before 1958 (Box 27, Folder 920)
        - Part I, bound copy, reviewed by John L. Pratt, 1958 Dec (Box 28, Folder 921)
        - Part I, bound copy, reviewed by O. E. Hunt, 1958 Dec (Box 28, Folder 922)
        - Part I, bound copy, reviewed by Charles Stewart Mott and Walker Evans, 1958 Dec (Box 28, Folder 923)
        - Part I, bound copy, with notes laid in, 1958 Dec (Box 28, Folder 924)
        - Part I, unbound copy, 1958 Dec (Box 28, Folder 925-927)
        - Part II, 1958 Dec (Box 29, Folder 928-929)
        - Sloan's approved edition, volume I (chapters 1-12), bound, 1959 June 16 (Box 29, Folder 930)
        - Sloan's approved edition, volume II (chapters 13-24), bound, 1959 June 16 (Box 29, Folder 931)
        - "Final Copy, John's Master Manuscript"
          - Volume 1, text, chapters 1-12, 1959 Sep (Box 29, Folder 932-934)
          - Volume 1, footnotes, 1959 Sep (Box 29, Folder 935)
          - Volume 1, quotations, 1959 Sep (Box 29, Folder 936)
          - Volume 2, text, chapters 13-24, 1959 Sep (Box 30, Folder 937-940)
          - Volume 2, quotations, 1959 Sep (Box 30, Folder 941)
      - Style and editing comments, 1958-1959 (Box 30, Folder 942)
      - "Spoof" newspaper, 1959
      - Settlement check, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 943)
      - Reviews, 1964-1995 (Box 30, Folder 944-946)
      - Royalty statements, all editions, 1964-1993 (Box 30, Folder 947-948)
      - Television program treatment proposal, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 949)
    - The Origins of Angling (1963, 1997)
      See also: "The Lady and the Trout," with Dwight A. Webster, May 27 and June 3, 1957
      - Correspondence
        - Binns, A. L., 1950-1964 (Box 30, Folder 950)
        - Bodleian Library, 1960-1962 (Box 30, Folder 951)
        - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1956-1970 (Box 30, Folder 952)
        - Easton Press, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 953-954)
        - Fellheimer, Jeannette, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 955)
        - Kuhn, Sherman M., 1957-1969 (Box 30, Folder 956-960)
        - Lyons, Nick and Tony, 1992-1997 (Box 30, Folder 961)
        - McPherson, John C., 1961, undated (Box 30, Folder 962)
        - Magnussen, Walter L., 1962 (Box 30, Folder 963)
        - Rice, Warner G., 1958-1962 (Box 30, Folder 964)
        - Webster, Dwight A., 1958-1963 (Box 30, Folder 965)
        - Miscellaneous correspondence and notes, 1957-1963 (Box 30, Folder 966)
      - Notes
        - Editorial notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 967)
        - "Notes for last glance", 1961 Nov (Box 30, Folder 968)
        - Miscellaneous notes from binder, undated (Box 30, Folder 969-970)
        - Miscellaneous notes, 1955-1963 (Box 30, Folder 971-974)
        - Miscellaneous notes, 1955-1963 (Box 31, Folder 975-978)
      - Original texts (photostat and photocopy sets)
        - Berners, pages removed from published book, annotated, undated (Box 31, Folder 979)
        - Bale on Berners, undated (Box 31, Folder 980)
        - Blades on Berners/Juliana Barnes (1906), undated (Box 31, Folder 981)
        - Berners' Treatise of Fishing with an Angle ([1515?]), 1956-1957, undated
        - Berners' Treatise of Fishing with an Angle (1803), undated
        - Berners' Treatise of Fishing with an Angle (1881), undated
        - Berners' Treatise of Fishing with an Angle (1885), undated
        - Biographia Britannica (1748), undated
        - Burton's Description of Leicester Shire, undated (Box 31, Folder 982)
        - Chauncey's Historical Antiquaries (1700), undated
        - Denison's Literal Translation (1872), undated
        - DeWorde's editions of St. Albans, undated
        - Edward, "Master of the Game" (1406?), undated
        - Ellis's Catalogue of Books on Angling (1811), undated (Box 31, Folder 983)
        - Hearne's notes from his copy of Book of St. Albans (1732), undated (Box 31, Folder 984)
        - Hemingford's History of the Edwards (1731), undated (Box 31, Folder 985)
        - Holinshed's Chronicles (1577), undated
        - Jacob on the Book of St. Albans (1944), undated
        - Leland's index, undated
        - Leland's itinerary (in Burton's hand), undated (Box 31, Folder 986)
        - Letters from Satchell to Denison (1883), undated
        - Mascall's Booke of Fishing (1590), undated (Box 31, Folder 987)
        - Pits, Historical Accounts (1619), undated (Box 31, Folder 988)
        - Sir Gawain and the Green Knight, undated (Box 31, Folder 989)
        - Smith's introduction to Leland's Itinerary (1906), undated
        - Miscellaneous entries from the Oxford English Dictionary, undated (Box 31, Folder 990)
        - Miscellaneous texts from journals, by Haskins and others, undated
      - First draft, undated (Box 31, Folder 991)
      - Reviews and notices, 1963-1997 (Box 31, Folder 992)
      - Fan mail, 1963-1977 (Box 31, Folder 993)
    - Quill Gordon (1972)
      - Correspondence
        - Alfred A. Knopf, 1970-1976 (Box 31, Folder 994-995)
        - Deren, James, 1970-1973 (Box 31, Folder 996)
          Concerning John Atherton's paintings
        - Little, Brown & Company, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 997)
        - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 998)
      - Research material
        - Bethune, George W. (1847), undated (Box 31, Folder 999)
        - Cotton, Charles (1676), undated (Box 31, Folder 1000-1001)
        - Forrester, Frank (1849), undated (Box 31, Folder 1002)
        - Holden, George Parker (1927), undated (Box 31, Folder 1003)
        - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 31, Folder 1004)
      - Typescript, circa 1971 (Box 31, Folder 1005-1010)
      - Index, circa 1971 (Box 31, Folder 1011)
      - Permissions, 1970-1972 (Box 31, Folder 1012)
      - Mechanicals, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 1013-1015)
      - Galleys, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 1016)
      - Blue lines, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 1017)
      - Reviews, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 1018)
      - Fan mail, 1972-1979 (Box 31, Folder 1019)
      - "Afterthoughts", 1973 (Box 31, Folder 1020)
    - Strategy in Poker, Business and War (1950)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1991 (Box 32, Folder 1021-1023)
      - Notes, draft pages, and galley sheets, 1949-1951, undated (Box 32, Folder 1024-1025)
      - Press notices, 1950, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 1026)
      - Fan mail, 1950-1962 (Box 32, Folder 1027)
      - Abridged version, in Omnibook magazine, 1950 Dec (Box 32, Folder 1028)
  - Other Writings
    - Fiction
      - "A", 1987, undated (Box 32, Folder 1029-1035)
      - "Borges on Morton Street", 1980, undated (Box 32, Folder 1036-1039)
      - "Daydream", 1979-1980 (Box 32, Folder 1040-1043)
      - "Epi _ _ _ [ear]", 1984-1986 (Box 33, Folder 1044-1050)
      - "Hairpin"/"Hairpins"
        - Hairpins (two), undated (Box 33, Folder 1051)
        - Notebooks and notes, 1988-1998 (Box 33, Folder 1052-1065)
        - Notebooks and notes, 1988-1998 (Box 34, Folder 1066-1075)
      - "Pelican"
        - Typescript and correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 34, Folder 1076)
        - Drafts and correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 34, Folder 1077-1080)
        - Mary McDonnell's mock-up, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 1081)
        - Notes, 1990-1991 (Box 34, Folder 1082-1085)
        - Children's books for examples, 1969, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 1086)
      - "Piloting", 1980-1998 (Box 34, Folder 1087-1088)
      - "Puffin", 1977-1981 (Box 34, Folder 1089-1090)
    - Non-fiction
      - "Applications of Game Theory in Business and Industry," paper for the annual meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, St. Louis, 1952-1965 (Box 34, Folder 1091-1092)
      - "Chainomania", 1938 (Box 34, Folder 1093)
      - "Detroit" projects
        - Early writings
          - Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 35, Folder 1094)
          - Notes, 1938-1939 (Box 35, Folder 1095-1096)
          - Outlines and essays, 1938-1939 (Box 35, Folder 1097-1102)
            Includes "Autotown," "Before the Automobile," "F.O.B. Detroit," and "The First Two Hundred Years"
        - Research and correspondence files
          - Brown family, 1980s (Box 35, Folder 1103)
          - Cape Breton, Nova Scotia, Canada, 1978-1985 (Box 35, Folder 1104-1105)
          - Drugstore handbill, 1944 (Box 35, Folder 1106)
          - Family compilation and chronology, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 1107)
          - LPG (League of Professional Groups for Foster and Ford), 1980s (Box 35, Folder 1108)
          - McDonald, John and John E., 1941 (Box 35, Folder 1109)
          - Maps, 1989-1980 (Box 35, Folder 1110)
          - Marriage records, 1981-1987 (Box 35, Folder 1111)
          - Matheson/McDonald family, 1940-1995 (Box 35, Folder 1112-1114)
          - Miami, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 1115)
          - Ontario, Canada, 1981-1986 (Box 35, Folder 1116-1119)
          - Perrin family, 1973-1983 (Box 35, Folder 1120-1121)
          - Polk directories, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 1122)
          - West Village Association (Detroit), 1981-1985 (Box 35, Folder 1123-1124)
          - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1982-1996 (Box 35, Folder 1125)
        - Notes
          - "Approach", 1980s (Box 35, Folder 1126-1127)
          - "1920s", 1980s (Box 35, Folder 1128)
          - "1930s", 1980s (Box 35, Folder 1129)
          - "First period", 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1130)
          - "Second period", 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1131)
          - "Third period", 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1132)
          - Miscellaneous notes, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1133-1151)
        - Photographs
          - McDonald drugstores, 1899-1982 (Box 36, Folder 1152)
          - McDonald, John E., tintype, circa 1890 (Box 36, Folder 1153)
          - McDonald family in backyard, with copy negatives and prints, circa 1909-1915, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1154)
          - McDonald family members, copy prints, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 1155)
          - Family members, miscellaneous, 1890-1981 (Box 36, Folder 1156)
          - Family at Perrin/McDonald farm, copy negatives and prints, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 1157)
          - Perrin and McDonald family members, copy negatives and prints, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1158)
          - Unidentified family members, copy negatives of tintypes held by Perrin family, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1159)
          - Mary Perrin McDonald and house on Forest Avenue, with copy negative and prints, circa 1910, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1160)
        - Outlines and drafts
          - Sketch, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1161)
          - "Memories of Growing Up in Detroit" outline, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 1162)
          - "Memories of Growing Up in Detroit", 1981 Oct (Box 36, Folder 1163)
          - "Memories of Growing Up in Detroit", 1981 Dec (Box 36, Folder 1164-1165)
          - "Memories of Growing Up in Detroit", 1982 July (Box 36, Folder 1166)
          - Miscellaneous draft pages, 1980s (Box 36, Folder 1167-1168)
      - Fishing articles, miscellaneous, some written with Dan Bailey, 1940-1941, undated (Box 36, Folder 1169-1170)
      - "Kriegsspiel (Double Blind Chess)", 1950-1975 (Box 36, Folder 1171)
      - United States, Air Force. Ballistic missile report, 1954-1958 (Box 36, Folder 1172)
- Other Papers, 1911-1998; Series III; 8.58; (9 boxes)